<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.7.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-08-07T10:44:57+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Turntabl</title><subtitle>turntabl is a software agency based in Accra, Ghana</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Guest Post: Christiana</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2019/11/20/guest-post-christiana.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Guest Post: Christiana" /><published>2019-11-20T17:26:04+00:00</published><updated>2019-11-20T17:26:04+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2019/11/20/guest-post-christiana</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2019/11/20/guest-post-christiana.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/christiana-1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Christiana&quot; title=&quot;Christiana in class at turntabl&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re just over halfway through our 9-week training program, so please enjoy this recap from Christiana:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During these past five weeks, the TLC program has been highly engaging and an awesome experience. This program bridges university education with real world projects. At university, it’s all about studying and taking exams but this training program has allowed me to apply what I learned. The comprehensive skills acquired through TLC so far has definitely provided me with the tools necessary as an up and coming Software Engineer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The entire program structure has been completely different from my undergraduate experience.  Within this short period, I have learnt technical skills, including programming languages like C++ and Java, Unix and SQL. In general, there has been a well balanced combination of lectures, presentations, lab sessions as well as working together in teams on interesting projects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The course itself is intensive and has not been easy. Some concepts took time to digest, and there were times that I got stuck. However, I’ve learned that being stuck is okay because a lot of software engineering for me has been working to solve complex issues I don’t quite understand, with confidence I don’t quite feel. But you stay for the challenge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, this program has been about more about understanding the underlying principles of software engineering, learning how to approach problems programmatically and above all learning how to learn. Another aspect is learning to work well in teams through presentations as well as using the various technological tools like git and TravisCI for continuous integration to track SDLC of a project. It’s been a great learning curve exploring these tools with other team members whilst adopting an agile approach.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;–
Thanks Christiana!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To find out more please contact us at &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:interest@turntabl.io&quot; class=&quot;link&quot;&gt;interest@turntabl.io&lt;/a&gt;.  We will provide a dedicated person to work with you on a best in class technology sourcing solution.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>turntablio</name></author><summary type="html"></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/images/christiana-1.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Guest Post: Doreen</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2019/11/20/guest-post-doreen.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Guest Post: Doreen" /><published>2019-11-20T17:26:04+00:00</published><updated>2019-11-20T17:26:04+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2019/11/20/guest-post-doreen</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2019/11/20/guest-post-doreen.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/doreen-1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Doreen&quot; title=&quot;Doreen in class at turntabl&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re about to finish our ten-week training program with two weeks of major group projects. Here’s an update from our associate Doreen:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My experience so far at  has been interesting. I am learning at an enormously fast rate than I have ever learnt before. Concepts I learnt in school are now beginning to sound very clear and much more comprehensible. In the first week of the training, we were taught some financial basics. Concepts like stocks, bonds, arbitrage, fractional and full reserve banking among others were well taught. We were later introduced to some C++. I already had some knowledge about it. All I knew was when you wanted to declare or initialize a value, you have to explicitly declare its data type. I honestly didn’t know why it had to that but I later came to understand that declaring its data type determines the amount of space that’s needed to store it in memory and also determines the kind of operations that can be done on it. We had some practice exercises that made us understand much better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The whole training program was designed in such a way that when we have a week of practical sessions, the subsequent week is much more theoretical and involved discussions amongst ourselves. We were divided into groups and given topics to research and prepare presentations to be delivered to the class every day after lunch. I really do not like presentations because I get very nervous when a handful of people look at me at once but since we did it for quite some time, I have learnt to live with it even though I still get nervous when it’s my turn to talk. We were introduced to agile development including creating user stories from requirements required by a client, attaching story points to the stories based on their levels of difficulty, conducting sprints and SCRUMs to work on the stories in stages, designing prototypes based on the user stories all the while keeping the client involved in most of these activities and also working as a team. At first, working as a team was rough because most of us were not used to working as a group and we also did not know our individual weaknesses so dividing work within us was a bit difficult.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We moved on into the world of object-oriented design with Java. We were taught how to model a problem by identifying objects and classes and the relationships that may exist between them. Our first Java project as a team was to design a command line client management system for TurnTabl. The application had to allow a user to be able to search for a client, add a new client, update a client and also delete a client from the system. Sam acted as the client we were working for and I must say he really did play his role quite well. For the past subsequent weeks, we have been introduced to Databases with postgresql where we modified our previous command line project to incorporate making calls to a database we created using the JDBC template. We were taught the importance of writing unit tests for any code we write and also working with continuous integration in our workflow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were introduced to using the Spring framework as a dependency injection as well as Swagga, A bit of data science with numpy and using jupyter notebooks, we had a brief introduction to Hadoop where we created clusters of four and in each cluster one of us acted as the master node and had control over the worker nodes and granted permissions to them in order to have access to resources on the distributed system. We were also introduced to Redis as a pub/sub system where we subscribed and published to channels we created and then reading messages published on those channels as well. Our next project was on building microservices where we deployed our applications on Heroku and then incorporating Redis to act as a pub/sub between our microservices so that each of the service would be notified as soon as a request is made. I won’t lie this project was complicated. We had to do lots of researching and figuring stuff out but in the end, we pulled through and ended up gaining much more knowledge in implementing Redis into an application. You can tell that we have actually been taught lots and lots of concepts and had lots of practice on what we have been taught and in fact we are still actually learning new stuff. We were currently introduced to Angular were we each revamped our previous project from the command line to a single page application.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have adopted some useful tips as developers as well. As developers, we always want to have our code compile successfully all the time but in reality we know that isn’t the case at all. Once we see those red lines appearing on our screens, we have this sinking feeling in our guts. I believe that the main reason why we hate to see error messages is because we don’t actually read them. Even though some reasons for the error messages are so annoying especially the ones you get when you forgot to add a semicolon somewhere and once you realize the cause of the errors was something so minute, we feel like just smashing our computers against the wall, most of them are quite helpful and even go as far as even giving you hints or suggestions on how to solve them. When I see error messages, I still get that sinking feeling but I now read them and know where to spot the exact error message among the other messages that are displayed.Our mantra here is ‘git add, git commit, git push’. Another helpful and significant work ethic we have adopted in the course of the training.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the major reasons I decided to join turntabl was because of the plan Sam has in relation to volunteering. When we actually start to work for clients, we dedicate a portion of our time to do some volunteering work which involves teaching ICT in some basic schools and also helping out in &lt;a href=&quot;https://globalcode.org.uk/&quot; class=&quot;link&quot;&gt;Global Code&lt;/a&gt;. We are currently in the last phase of the training where we will be given projects to work on for two whole weeks. I seriously don’t know what to expect but one thing I know is that it’s going to be one heck of a project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;–&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks Doreen! If you’re interested in working with turntabl please &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:sales@globalcode.org.uk&quot; class=&quot;link&quot;&gt;get in touch!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>turntablio</name></author><summary type="html"></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/images/doreen-1.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Why work with turntabl?</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2019/09/04/why-work-with-turntabl.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Why work with turntabl?" /><published>2019-09-04T17:26:04+00:00</published><updated>2019-09-04T17:26:04+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2019/09/04/why-work-with-turntabl</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2019/09/04/why-work-with-turntabl.html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;why-turntabl&quot;&gt;Why Turntabl?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Turntabl is a technical partner that combines decades of Fortune 500 technology and training experience with a track record in Ghana. We provide highly motivated engineers managed by staff seasoned in western companies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Engineers will become available in January 2020: now is a great time to start working with turntabl to create value for money technology sourcing for your company.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;ghana-is-emerging-as-a-great-place-to-do-business&quot;&gt;Ghana is emerging as a great place to do business&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a compelling business case for Western companies to benefit from the opportunities that can currently be found in Ghana. It is a stable multi-party democracy which has seen successive peaceful transitions of power. Accra, the capital city, is safe and accessible, with modern internet and office facilities. Corruption is the lowest in the region – lower than some large European states.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Situated in West Africa close to the Greenwich meridian, Ghana spends half the year in the same time zone as the United Kingdom and the other half on Central European Time. Your turntabl colleagues can work closely and effectively with staff in London and the rest of Europe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the official language, English is spoken widely and fluently – higher education is conducted in English. Generally, levels of spoken English and comprehension are higher than other popular technology locations such as India, China and Mexico.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Turntabl’s unique blend of proven expertise from Western companies and local knowledge will deliver the cost and capability benefits of Ghana to your business on a sound ethical basis that we can all be proud to participate in. Read more about the ethical aspect of our work in Ghana &lt;a href=&quot;/aims&quot; class=&quot;link&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;how-turntabl-delivers-the-promise-of-ghana-to-a-business&quot;&gt;How Turntabl delivers the promise of Ghana to a business&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Working alongside &lt;a href=&quot;https://globalcode.org.uk/&quot; class=&quot;link&quot;&gt;Global Code&lt;/a&gt;, we’ve already built a region-leading talent pipeline. We work hard to locate and recruit talented young people, and we provide them with mentoring, support, and volunteering and teaching opportunities in their university years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We then invite select students to join turntabl and participate in our multi-month training programme. Using our many years of experience in graduate training for Fortune 500 companies we have carefully crafted a programme to meet the demands of modern IT.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The programme is challenging and invigorating for the students, bringing them to a high international standard. When companies engage with us we offer to tailor the training programme to meet their specific needs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After long successful careers in technology in the West, many people look for a new and exciting challenge. Often those people want to do something that will make a social difference in the world. At Turntabl we offer people a chance to do that by managing our upcoming engineers in Ghana. Having teams managed by experienced professionals enables us to provide a high quality outcome for our clients.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our first group will be ready to work in January 2020. By engaging with Turntabl now, your business can tailor low cost, high quality technology provision, at the same time knowing it is done on a sustainable ethical basis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;provision-at-scale&quot;&gt;Provision at scale&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We expect our annual staff intake to be able to more than double each year. With active recruitment yet to begin for 2020 we already have dozens of prospective employees. Our ability to scale means that we make a great partner for even the largest enterprises.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While Ghana is already a great place for businesses, the medium term opportunity is equally significant. Unlike competing economies in the same time zone in Europe, Ghana has a young population. Well over 50% of the population are under 25. With more than six times as many under-25s as popular outsourcing locations Hungary or the Czech republic, Ghana is growing 10 times faster than the EU.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This pool of youthful talent will provide engineers for years to come. Working with turntabl now enables you to get acquainted with the landscape in Ghana while reaping real benefits today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To find out more please contact us at &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:interest@turntabl.io&quot; class=&quot;link&quot;&gt;interest@turntabl.io&lt;/a&gt;.  We will provide a dedicated person to work with you on a best in class technology sourcing solution.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Why Turntabl?</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Africa is not a country (again)</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2019/06/17/africa-is-not-a-country.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Africa is not a country (again)" /><published>2019-06-17T17:26:04+00:00</published><updated>2019-06-17T17:26:04+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2019/06/17/africa-is-not-a-country</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2019/06/17/africa-is-not-a-country.html">&lt;p&gt;We are not the first to comment on the lazy habit of some of those in the West who accidentally view Africa as a single country.  Prominent politicians and other public figures have been called out for this slip of the tongue, and many media articles have described the damage that this mindset causes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whilst we’ve been setting up Turntabl, we’ve encountered this habit more than once.  Sometimes it shows itself through the seemingly innocuous question, ‘What are you doing in Africa?’ Experience in one of the more than 50 countries that make up this enormous and diverse continent is regarded as experience in Africa.  The problem is laid bare when this question is extended to the statement, ‘we don’t do business in Africa because…’ Ghana is conflated with Africa, and Africa is written off for business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This doesn’t seem to apply in other parts of the world. Ghana has higher international transparency scores than Italy, but business is happy to trade in Europe.  Mexico has a far higher violent crime rate than Ghana, but this is not translated to a wider problem with doing business in the Americas.  The USA is not judged on the corruption, violence or instability that causes problems in other parts of that continent, but it seems that Ghana is often viewed in light of the problems that face some of the other countries in Africa.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our concern is that the beliefs that lead to this view are consciously or unconsciously held more widely by businesses in the West.  Where it is visible, or overtly stated, we can see how it is stopping international companies from benefiting from the wealth of talent and the youthful demographic that we have found in Ghana.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve chosen to set up Turntable in Ghana because we think that companies all over the world can benefit from working with this exciting country.  We have found great engineers here who will deliver benefit to any company they work in.  More than 50% of the population is under 24.  English is widely spoken, corruption is low and falling, the education system is producing a competent, growing, youthful and enthusiastic middle class.  Knowledge-based businesses run off of the quality of the people they can employ.  In the coming decades Ghana offers a bright future for any company wishing to operate here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are sure that businesses who overcome old habits of mind about the nature of ‘Africa’ will be as excited as we are about the engineering talent in Ghana and will be able to enjoy the huge benefits of doing business here.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">We are not the first to comment on the lazy habit of some of those in the West who accidentally view Africa as a single country. Prominent politicians and other public figures have been called out for this slip of the tongue, and many media articles have described the damage that this mindset causes.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Turntabl - Internet Connectivity in Accra</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2019/04/15/turntabl-connectivity.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Turntabl - Internet Connectivity in Accra" /><published>2019-04-15T17:26:04+00:00</published><updated>2019-04-15T17:26:04+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2019/04/15/turntabl-connectivity</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2019/04/15/turntabl-connectivity.html">&lt;p&gt;As an IT services company, we’re absolutely dependent on an internet connection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Internet connectivity in Ghana is not brilliant. Until recently, there were two major mobile providers:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vodafone has good coverage around most of the south of the country, but was only 3G&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;MTN has great 4G coverage in Accra, but very poor coverage elsewhere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recently, MTN has marketed TurboNet, a 4G/WiFi Bridge supposedly delivering blazing-fast broadband with excellent uptime. We’ve been testing one of these around the country and so far the claims hold up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In response, Vodafone has “upgraded” its network to 4G (read: they flipped a switch), so you can get LTE in Accra on Vodafone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What we’re really looking for, though, is supplier diversity. Vodafone’s consumer network has suffered horrifying outages in Q1 2019, so it’s important we don’t depend on a single supplier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The final option is digging the road up and getting fibre into the office. This would make for much greater capital outlay and would restrict potential office sites. Once we grow above 20 people it’s likely we’ll need to consider this option too.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">As an IT services company, we’re absolutely dependent on an internet connection.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Turntabl - April Progress</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2019/04/01/turntabl-april-progress.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Turntabl - April Progress" /><published>2019-04-01T17:26:04+00:00</published><updated>2019-04-01T17:26:04+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2019/04/01/turntabl-april-progress</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2019/04/01/turntabl-april-progress.html">&lt;p&gt;In these posts we’re hoping to give brief updates as to what we’re doing and what progress we’re making.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Turntabl group has two goals: firstly, to be a software agency delivering high quality results in the Western market. And secondly, to be a premium employer to young developers in Ghana.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By achieving these goals, we also hope to build a strong culture of Giving Back, through which we’ll make concrete positive changes in the lives of our employees, their families, and the wider community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ll start operations in mid-October, and to that end we’ve been working hard behind the scenes to make it all happen. Here’s what we’ve done so far:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We’ve set up a company in the UK, Turntabl Ltd, which will attract clients and collect invoices.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Turntabl Ghana will hire developers and prepare them for professional work.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ghana has compulsory National Service for new graduates, so we’re going to set ourselves up as a National Service employer.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We’re looking for office space in Accra! Our office needs to be accessible to all our employees, and it needs to have great internet.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Meanwhile, we’re preparing training material for a 10-week training program to be delivered before Christmas&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;And finally, we’re hiring! We aim to have 20 employees in Ghana by October and currently we have 13 fully signed up.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s very exciting, and there’s a lot more to do, but we’re all very proud with our progress.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">In these posts we’re hoping to give brief updates as to what we’re doing and what progress we’re making.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Turntabl - A Sustainable Enterprise</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2019/03/20/turntabl-a-sustainable-enterprise.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Turntabl - A Sustainable Enterprise" /><published>2019-03-20T17:26:04+00:00</published><updated>2019-03-20T17:26:04+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2019/03/20/turntabl-a-sustainable-enterprise</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2019/03/20/turntabl-a-sustainable-enterprise.html">&lt;p&gt;We’re setting up Turntabl to make a difference in Ghana. It is our aim to develop a sustainable enterprise with a quality focus and a global outlook. We aim for Turntabl to provide all the employees, including ourselves, with a good wage. At the same time we want to make as much positive change as possible. Ultimately we intend to part with the company, giving it away so that its wealth creation can benefit Ghana to the fullest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the words of the song, ‘Life is what happens to you while you’re busy making other plans,’ but we still feel it is important to have a stated direction. Along the way things may change. Maybe another opportunity to improve the situation in another country will emerge. Maybe we will be called back to our families, or maybe the idea will prove to be non-viable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whatever happens we want to make this initial statement; to use it as a reminder of our original goals, and as something to measure ourselves against.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-is-turntabl-as-a-business&quot;&gt;What is Turntabl as a business?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Turntabl will be a quality driven software consultancy company. We will operate and compete in the premium part of the software consultancy market. Our focus will be on hiring relatively small numbers of the best people. With more than 30 years combined experience at the quality end of the software market we believe we can teach our graduate recruits in Ghana how to function and excel in that arena.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each year we will seek out the best people we can find in Ghana and employ them. We will train them to be excellent engineers. Those people will then be able to compete for work in the global market for technology engineering talent. We intend to form deep quality-based relationships with our customer organisations. We will rival the quality consulting organisations of the technology industry, not the cheaper ones. Our intention is to start with 20 engineers in 2019 and steadily increase our intake to more than 100 engineers each year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our hope is that by 2029 we will employ 1000 engineers in Ghana.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;treating-our-employees-correctly&quot;&gt;Treating our employees correctly&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our employees should expect to be treated with dignity and respect. Turntabl employees will receive an excellent remuneration package, with benefits including health insurance, emergency child care cover and other common employee assistance programmes. We will provide a world class training programme on entry to Turntabl. Spread over a number of months this will allow our staff to operate at the very high end of the technology industry. We will continue to make time for our staff to improve their skills with both formal and informal learning opportunities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Turntabl will be a family friendly, equal opportunity employer. We will provide parental leave for women and men. We will make extra effort to seek out those people in disadvantaged groups, such as women and disabled people. We think that intelligence and capability lies everywhere. When we find intelligent people that other companies would not employ, both Turntabl and the employee will gain from that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Within the company we will create an environment free of discrimination and fear, striving to make our work environment the most inclusive - not only in Ghana, but in the world. We will do this not only because it is the right thing, but because we think that it will make us more attractive to the best people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each year, as part of the compensation system of Turntabl, employees will receive shares in the company. Employees will act with pride and responsibility towards the company they part own.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-will-turntabl-behave-towards-the-outside-world&quot;&gt;How will Turntabl behave towards the outside world&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have already gained so much personally from the fantastic people of Ghana. We expect the business to be a rewarding personal experience for ourselves and for the other employees. As such we feel that all of us at Turntabl will always owe an obligation to the people of Ghana. What that means is that each of us have to find a way to give back to the country.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a company we will make that part of our operation; our staff will seek out - and help to grow and nurture - the next generation of engineers from every part of Ghanian society. They will use company time and resources to help with the education of the next generation of Ghanians. Over time Turntabl will divert significant amounts of its revenue to charitable causes operating in Ghana and across the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We hope to attract staff that are inspired to use their own time and energy in similar endevours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Turntabl will not seek to lower its tax bill. We expect the business model to be strong enough that it will not require any help to get off the ground and thrive. As such we will not be taking advantage of the government’s excellent Ghana Free Zones policy. This should leave more resources available to the government to encourage other businesses in the country.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Similarly we will not engage in corruption. We will not pay or take bribes to change our behaviour. Ghana has made huge strides towards ridding itself of corruption and we will do everything we can to help support that aim.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-relationship-of-the-founders-to-turntabl&quot;&gt;The relationship of the founders to Turntabl&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We do not want people to read this and view Turntabl as an act of pure altruism. We also need to earn a living for our families, and Turntabl is a business. We expect Turntabl to provide us with a reasonable remuneration for our work - however, we do not expect to be able to sell out of Turntabl and become rich based on the efforts of others. When Turntabl does become viable we will expect to reclaim our startup costs, and be paid for the work we have done and continue to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we stop working for Turntabl we will stop financially benefitting from it. Employees will already own a large part of the company, possibly all of it. Should any ownership remain with us we will transfer it to employees or to a trust that serves our social vision.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">We’re setting up Turntabl to make a difference in Ghana. It is our aim to develop a sustainable enterprise with a quality focus and a global outlook. We aim for Turntabl to provide all the employees, including ourselves, with a good wage. At the same time we want to make as much positive change as possible. Ultimately we intend to part with the company, giving it away so that its wealth creation can benefit Ghana to the fullest.</summary></entry></feed>