<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.7.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-04-22T11:03:05+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Turntabl</title><subtitle>Write an awesome description for your new site here. You can edit this line in _config.yml. It will appear in your document head meta (for Google search results) and in your feed.xml site description.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Turntabl - Internet Connectivity in Accra</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2019/04/15/turntabl-connectivity.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Turntabl - Internet Connectivity in Accra" /><published>2019-04-15T18:26:04+01:00</published><updated>2019-04-15T18:26:04+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2019/04/15/turntabl-connectivity</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2019/04/15/turntabl-connectivity.html">&lt;p&gt;As an IT services company, we’re absolutely dependent on an internet connection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Internet connectivity in Ghana is not brilliant. Until recently, there were two major mobile providers:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vodafone has good coverage around most of the south of the country, but was only 3G&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;MTN has great 4G coverage in Accra, but very poor coverage elsewhere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recently, MTN has marketed TurboNet, a 4G/WiFi Bridge supposedly delivering blazing-fast broadband with excellent uptime. We’ve been testing one of these around the country and so far the claims hold up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In response, Vodafone has “upgraded” its network to 4G (read: they flipped a switch), so you can get LTE in Accra on Vodafone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What we’re really looking for, though, is supplier diversity. Vodafone’s consumer network has suffered horrifying outages in Q1 2019, so it’s important we don’t depend on a single supplier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The final option is digging the road up and getting fibre into the office. This would make for much greater capital outlay and would restrict potential office sites. Once we grow above 20 people it’s likely we’ll need to consider this option too.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">As an IT services company, we’re absolutely dependent on an internet connection.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Turntabl - April Progress</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2019/04/01/turntabl-april-progress.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Turntabl - April Progress" /><published>2019-04-01T18:26:04+01:00</published><updated>2019-04-01T18:26:04+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2019/04/01/turntabl-april-progress</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2019/04/01/turntabl-april-progress.html">&lt;p&gt;In these posts we’re hoping to give brief updates as to what we’re doing and what progress we’re making.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Turntabl group has two goals: firstly, to be a software agency delivering high quality results in the Western market. And secondly, to be a premium employer to young developers in Ghana.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By achieving these goals, we also hope to build a strong culture of Giving Back, through which we’ll make concrete positive changes in the lives of our employees, their families, and the wider community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ll start operations in mid-October, and to that end we’ve been working hard behind the scenes to make it all happen. Here’s what we’ve done so far:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We’ve set up a company in the UK, Turntabl Ltd, which will attract clients and collect invoices.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Turntabl Ghana will hire developers and prepare them for professional work.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ghana has compulsory National Service for new graduates, so we’re going to set ourselves up as a National Service employer.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We’re looking for office space in Accra! Our office needs to be accessible to all our employees, and it needs to have great internet.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Meanwhile, we’re preparing training material for a 10-week training program to be delivered before Christmas&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;And finally, we’re hiring! We aim to have 20 employees in Ghana by October and currently we have 13 fully signed up.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s very exciting, and there’s a lot more to do, but we’re all very proud with our progress.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">In these posts we’re hoping to give brief updates as to what we’re doing and what progress we’re making.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Turntabl - A Sustainable Enterprise</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2019/03/20/turntabl-a-sustainable-enterprise.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Turntabl - A Sustainable Enterprise" /><published>2019-03-20T17:26:04+00:00</published><updated>2019-03-20T17:26:04+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2019/03/20/turntabl-a-sustainable-enterprise</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2019/03/20/turntabl-a-sustainable-enterprise.html">&lt;p&gt;We’re setting up Turntabl to make a difference in Ghana. It is our aim to develop a sustainable enterprise with a quality focus and a global outlook. We aim for Turntabl to provide all the employees, including ourselves, with a good wage. At the same time we want to make as much positive change as possible. Ultimately we intend to part with the company, giving it away so that its wealth creation can benefit Ghana to the fullest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the words of the song, ‘Life is what happens to you while you’re busy making other plans,’ but we still feel it is important to have a stated direction. Along the way things may change. Maybe another opportunity to improve the situation in another country will emerge. Maybe we will be called back to our families, or maybe the idea will prove to be non-viable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whatever happens we want to make this initial statement; to use it as a reminder of our original goals, and as something to measure ourselves against.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-is-turntabl-as-a-business&quot;&gt;What is Turntabl as a business?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Turntabl will be a quality driven software consultancy company. We will operate and compete in the premium part of the software consultancy market. Our focus will be on hiring relatively small numbers of the best people. With more than 30 years combined experience at the quality end of the software market we believe we can teach our graduate recruits in Ghana how to function and excel in that arena.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each year we will seek out the best people we can find in Ghana and employ them. We will train them to be excellent engineers. Those people will then be able to compete for work in the global market for technology engineering talent. We intend to form deep quality-based relationships with our customer organisations. We will rival the quality consulting organisations of the technology industry, not the cheaper ones. Our intention is to start with 20 engineers in 2019 and steadily increase our intake to more than 100 engineers each year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our hope is that by 2029 we will employ 1000 engineers in Ghana.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;treating-our-employees-correctly&quot;&gt;Treating our employees correctly&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our employees should expect to be treated with dignity and respect. Turntabl employees will receive an excellent remuneration package, with benefits including health insurance, emergency child care cover and other common employee assistance programmes. We will provide a world class training programme on entry to Turntabl. Spread over a number of months this will allow our staff to operate at the very high end of the technology industry. We will continue to make time for our staff to improve their skills with both formal and informal learning opportunities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Turntabl will be a family friendly, equal opportunity employer. We will provide parental leave for women and men. We will make extra effort to seek out those people in disadvantaged groups, such as women and disabled people. We think that intelligence and capability lies everywhere. When we find intelligent people that other companies would not employ, both Turntabl and the employee will gain from that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Within the company we will create an environment free of discrimination and fear, striving to make our work environment the most inclusive - not only in Ghana, but in the world. We will do this not only because it is the right thing, but because we think that it will make us more attractive to the best people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each year, as part of the compensation system of Turntabl, employees will receive shares in the company. Employees will act with pride and responsibility towards the company they part own.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-will-turntabl-behave-towards-the-outside-world&quot;&gt;How will Turntabl behave towards the outside world&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have already gained so much personally from the fantastic people of Ghana. We expect the business to be a rewarding personal experience for ourselves and for the other employees. As such we feel that all of us at Turntabl will always owe an obligation to the people of Ghana. What that means is that each of us have to find a way to give back to the country.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a company we will make that part of our operation; our staff will seek out - and help to grow and nurture - the next generation of engineers from every part of Ghanian society. They will use company time and resources to help with the education of the next generation of Ghanians. Over time Turntabl will divert significant amounts of its revenue to charitable causes operating in Ghana and across the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We hope to attract staff that are inspired to use their own time and energy in similar endevours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Turntabl will not seek to lower its tax bill. We expect the business model to be strong enough that it will not require any help to get off the ground and thrive. As such we will not be taking advantage of the government’s excellent Ghana Free Zones policy. This should leave more resources available to the government to encourage other businesses in the country.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Similarly we will not engage in corruption. We will not pay or take bribes to change our behaviour. Ghana has made huge strides towards ridding itself of corruption and we will do everything we can to help support that aim.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-relationship-of-the-founders-to-turntabl&quot;&gt;The relationship of the founders to Turntabl&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We do not want people to read this and view Turntabl as an act of pure altruism. We also need to earn a living for our families, and Turntabl is a business. We expect Turntabl to provide us with a reasonable remuneration for our work - however, we do not expect to be able to sell out of Turntabl and become rich based on the efforts of others. When Turntabl does become viable we will expect to reclaim our startup costs, and be paid for the work we have done and continue to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we stop working for Turntabl we will stop financially benefitting from it. Employees will already own a large part of the company, possibly all of it. Should any ownership remain with us we will transfer it to employees or to a trust that serves our social vision.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">We’re setting up Turntabl to make a difference in Ghana. It is our aim to develop a sustainable enterprise with a quality focus and a global outlook. We aim for Turntabl to provide all the employees, including ourselves, with a good wage. At the same time we want to make as much positive change as possible. Ultimately we intend to part with the company, giving it away so that its wealth creation can benefit Ghana to the fullest.</summary></entry></feed>